你确定不想像
You sure you didn't want to going back to earth
麦凯他们回地球度假
Like mckay and the others?
星门控制中心没有零点模块
Nah, sgc doesn't have a zpm,
所以  地球这两周
So two weeks on earth
就像困在泰达路斯(迷宫建筑师)的迷宫三周
Means three weeks cooped up in the daedalus.
相当于缺席五周
That's five weeks of missing work.
我们工作一年半才有休假
We only get one of those every year-and-a-half,
我宁愿留着  等到特殊情况再放假
So I'd like to save mine for something more special.
我们要去宿营吗
So we're going camping instead?
到一个从没被人发现的沙滩冲浪
On a beach that's never been surfed or even touched.
不是更能令人振奋吗
You gotta get more excited about this.
喂  快看
Hey, check that out.
怎么
What?
你猜他会有所行动吗
Think he'll ever make a move?
管他的
Who cares?
话说...
Say...
我们一年才能待在地球14天
I know we only get 14 days on earth a year,
你肯定很想念你父亲
And you miss your dad and all...
你想说...
But...
我有个老...
See, one of my old--
一个和我一起
A guy who was doing his doctorate
读博士的人
At the same time as me,
他将要做一次关于他最近研究
He's giving a big secret presentation
的秘密演讲
About some new thing that he's working on,
所有物理界的巨头
And everyone and anyone in the physics community
都会出席
Is going to be there.
而后...
And... well...
其实...
See, the thing is
我不由得有个想法
There's this perception out there
觉得自己
That I'm,
很失败  可有可无
Like, a washout, recluse...
怎么说
Why?
这是我赖以谋生的方法
Well, 'cause I do this for a living.
研究秘密顶尖技术
I mean, super double tip-top secret stuff.
近十年
I mean, I haven't published a paper
我还没发表过什么论文
In nearly a decade--
没有发表过任何公众读物
Not one that can be read by the general public--
连这外星系的生活什么的
And I'm kind of hard to get ahold of,
我也应接不暇
What with living in another galaxy and all.
我知道你的感受
Yeah, I know what that's like.
就是  他们觉得我不合群
Exactly. they think I'm a shut-in.
所以说...我在想...
So... I was thinking...
如果我能带个女士...一起去
That if I was to, say, show up... with a woman...
还是一个...美女
A-- a beautiful woman...
他们也许不会觉得
That they wouldn't maybe--
我是个彻底的失败者
Not think that I was... like, a complete loser.
其实才一天
Like, it would be one day,
在那里过一个晚上
The first night we were there,
第二天就可以启程去齐佩瓦瀑布
And then you could be off to chippewa falls.
说不定很有趣
I mean, it could be fun.
让我想想
Hmm. well, let's see--
满屋的物理学家
A room full of physicists,
一个啰啰嗦嗦的演讲
A long-winded presentation
或许我还听不懂
I probably won't understand...
听上去不怎么有趣
Yeah, doesn't really sound like fun.
或许那里会有酒水供应
Well, there'll be drinks, probably,
还有三明治
And maybe those little sandwiches...
还有...我
And... me.
我也会去
I'll be there.
你不必刻意编造理由
You don't have to fabricate all these reasons
约我出去
On why you need me to be with you.
直接约我就是了
You could just ask me out on a date.
我并不是想...
Hey, I didn't want to--
我是说 我知道你...
I mean, I know you--
或许我就答应了呢
I'll probably say yes.
那么...你愿意赏脸跟我去吗
Well, you... want to go to this thing with me?
好
Sure.
荣幸之至
I'd love to.
我也很...我是说...那...
Well, I'd love-- I mean, that's--
很好  不错  太好了  那是...
Good. good. great. that's--
就这么定了
It's a date.
那是关于什么的演讲
So what's the presentation?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们去到之前他都想保持神秘
He doesn't want to tell anyone until we all get there,
如果我认识他
But if I know this guy,
我就会说那是二流科学的
It'll be, uh, you know, first-class presentation...
一流演绎
With, like, second-rate science.
可能还有些"旁征博引"的成分
Probably some minor adjustment to someone else's work,
那里的食物肯定不错
But the food'll be good.
同伴也是
And the company.
迈尔克姆  你看过这个吗
Malcolm, have you read this?
看了
Yes.
你的下属认为
Your staff thinks it's reckless
明天启动仪器不太明智
To turn this thing on tomorrow.
少数人而已
Some of my staff...
迈尔克姆
Malcolm...
一些胆小鼠辈罢了
They're just getting cold feet, that's all.
还记得他们在瑟恩启动液氢容器时
Do you remember all that stuff that came out
他们都纷纷离开了吗
Before cern turned on the lhc?
你也知道  黑洞缩影
You know, miniature black holes,
外来粒子
Exotic particles,
太空金属
Strangelets,
星球瞬间毁灭
The instantaneous destruction of the planet?
全都是无稽的闹剧
All unfounded histrionics.
我们会没事的
We are going to be just fine.
你的意思是
So you're saying
这些潜在灾难都不会发生吗
None of these potential catastrophes will happen?
总有那么微小的一点机会
Well, there is always the slight possibility
某个部分会出错
That something might go wrong.
后果将会不堪设想
The cause has a lot riding on this.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
你所谓的后果
Your precious "cause"
明天就会消失得一干二净
Will come out of this squeaky clean tomorrow.
那些最坏打算的后果
Some of these worst-case scenarios
令人毛骨悚然
Are terrifying--
那当然
Of course they're terrifying--
因为那是最坏打算
They're worst-case scenarios!
是有可能发生
They are the worst possible thing
最坏的事
That could ever happen, ever.
明天会一切顺利的
Tomorrow will come off without a hitch.
我们做了很多试验
We've done hundreds of tests.
不可能失败
There is zero possibility for failure.
相信我
Trust me.
真让人兴奋
This is exciting.
飞机罢了
Well, it's just a plane.
但我从未做过头等舱
Yeah, but I've never even flown first class.
太奇妙了
This is amazing.
尝过这些草莓吗
Have you tried these strawberries?
10岁的时候
When I was 10,
我吃了整整一碗
I ate a bowl full of strawberries
还吐了
And threw up.
到现在还不能消化草莓
I haven't been able to stomach them since.
他怎么可以付得起这些行头
How does this guy afford all this?
我还以为他是个物理学家而已
I thought he was just a physicist.
他总能说服
Well, he was always able
大腕投资
To dupe guys with deep pockets in
他的研究计划
To backing his research.
光靠甜美的笑容和幻灯片
It's amazing what a nice smile and a power point presentation
是不足以打动你
Will get you.
我现在很满意
Well, I am impressed.
是的
Yes,
我看得出
I can see that.
拜托
Oh, come on.
朋友飞黄腾达  你应当高兴
You should be happy for your friend's success.
我与他只是
Well, it's more of an acquaintance
泛泛之交
Than a friend.
萍水相逢才不会用私人飞机接你
Acquaintances don't pick you up in private planes.
他这样做不是为了示好
He didn't send the jet to be nice.
而是给我个下马威
He sent the jet to rub it in my face.
在学校  我悟性总是
I was always one step ahead of this guy
胜他一筹
During school,
现在来到现实世界
And now that we're in the "real world,"
他想向我证明
He wants to show me that,
就这个星球而言
As far as most of the planet is concerned,
他的成就比我高得多
He's a lot more successful than I am.
还有  看这身晚装
And what is with the evening attire?
看在老天的份上  我们是去参加学术讲座
I mean, we're going to a science talk, for god's sake.
他以为自己是老几
Who the hell does he think he is?
你准备接下来的一整天
Is this what the whole day will be like?
你都要这样喋喋不休吗
Are you going to be in a bad mood?
不
No.
我们回到地球  乘坐着私人飞机
'cause we're back on earth on a private jet,
品尝着奢华的香槟
Drinking expensive champagne,
你的女伴穿着华丽的晚礼服
And your date's wearing a fancy dress.
罗德尼  换了是别人  他们一定很尽兴
Most people would be having a good time, rodney.
你说的对  你说得是
You're right. you're right...
麦凯
Mckay.
罗德尼·麦凯博士
Dr. rodney mckay.
珍妮弗·凯勒医生
Dr. jennifer keller.
欢迎
Yes. welcome.
现在  你们需要
I'll just need you both
签署这份保密协议
To sign this non-disclosure and confidentiality agreement.
不是吧
You're not serious.
有问题吗  先生
Is there a problem, sir?
还要什么保密协议
This whole thing is a confidentiality agreement?
是
Yes, sir.
他在做什么研究
What could they possibly be doing back there
连协议都有上200页
That needs to be kept 200 pages secret?
如果你想进去  就要先签协议
If you want to go inside, sir, you need to sign the agreement.
恐龙吗
Dinosaurs?
什么
Excuse me?
里面有活生生的恐龙吗
Do they have living dinosaurs back there?
如果他令恐龙回生
Because I'll sign this
我肯定会签
If he's brought dinosaurs back to life.
若不是如此  他肯定在发傻
But short of that, he is out of his mind
以为我不管他的研究是什么
If he thinks that I am going to pretend
都值得我去为他保密
That whatever discovery he's made
还要签署
Is so important and so secret
这份像莎翁名著那么厚的
That I have to sign the unabridged works
保密协议吗
Of william shakespeare here.
快签
Just sign it.
来吧
Here you go.
真幸运  有美女替你说话  是吧
Oh. you're just lucky the lady's here, aren't you?
我认为我们这是在哪里
Where do you think we are?
不知道  亚利桑那州  内华达
I don't know. arizona? nevada?
我不觉得
I didn't think
这里有什么秘密装置
People even built secret facilities anymore.
这里那么复古
It seems so 1950s.
罗德尼·麦凯
Rodney mckay?
根据可靠情报  你已经挂了
I had it on good authority that you were dead.
这位是你的...妹妹吗
And this would be your... sister?
不  尼尔  这不是我妹妹
No, no, neil. she's not my sister.
她是珍妮弗·凯勒
This is jennifer keller.
这是比尔·耐  这是尼尔·迪格斯·泰森
That's bill nye and neil degrasse tyson.
电视明星
You know, from television.
对啊  当然
Yeah, uh-- of course.
很高兴见到你
Very nice to meet you.
不  这该我说
No, pleasure's mine.
她名花有主了  尼尔
And she's taken, neil.
不  我没那意思
No, no, I didn't mean it that way--
尼尔最喜欢抢我的东西
Neil likes to steal things from me,
比方说女人和理论物理学思想
Things like women and theoretical physics ideas.
是的  谁不想借用
Yeah, but who hasn't stolen an idea
伟大的罗德尼·麦凯的思想呢
From the great rodney mckay?
你总算认了
Oh, so we admit it now.
想当年
See, back in the day,
每当有人有什么新见解
Whenever any one of these people came up with a new idea
或者发表了什么文章
Or published a new paper,
他就会信誓旦旦的说
Dr. mckay here would swear
跟他的研究如出一辙
That he was already working on something very similar,
只是还没来得及发表
Just hadn't gotten around to publishing it yet.
他就会说
He'd say things like,
"我正想说这个"
"i was about to say that very same thing,"
或者是"我刚刚想的和这个一样"
Or, "i was just about to have That same idea."
至少我不会将冥王星从行星中删除
At least I didn't declassify pluto from planet status.
尼尔  把孩子弄哭
Way to make all the little kids cry, neil.
就让你觉得很伟大吗
That make you feel like a big man?
多亏泰森博士
See, thanks to dr. tyson,
冥王星被赋予新的状态
Pluto is now the first of the plutoids,
新一级的天体
A new class of celestial object.
太好了
It's cool.
别这样  罗德尼
Come on, rodney.
这是21世纪
It's the 21st century.
事实上  仔细想想
Actually, come to think of it,
你上次发表论文在什么时候
When was the last time you even published a paper?
80年代?
The '80s?
没有那么久吧
It hasn't been that long.
当时读它时
I think I was listening
我就像在看
To that band a flock of seagulls
一群海鸥乐队唱大戏
While I was reading it.
事实上  你的论文吹的真是天花乱坠
Actually, it might have been pre-reagan.
是吗  真有幸你们读了我的论文
Well, it has been great running into you guys.
我们要去找座位了
We should maybe get our seats.
再见
Bye.
他们俩不可能在约会!
They can't possibly be dating.
是啊
I know.
那么  既然你已经结婚了  那
Well, you're married, so...
Dibs.
她是你的了
She's all yours.
我想不应该来这儿
I think maybe this was a bad idea.
为什么
Why?
我突然觉得
Well, I just remembered
自己并不太喜欢这些人
I don't really like these people.
是你不喜欢他们呢
Is it that you don't like them,
还是他们不喜欢你
Or maybe they don't like you?
可能吧
Possibly.
我是说  我过去有点要强
I mean, I used to be a little... abrasive?
以前啊
Oh, used to be. yeah.
不好解释
It's hard to explain.
我的领域竞争很激烈
My field is very competitive.
是吗  我读了六年医
Yeah, I went to med school  For six years.
不太了解这方面事
I wouldn't know anything about that.
是啊
Oh... right.
不是每件事
Not everything
都得这么争的  罗德尼
Has to be a competition, rodney.
他们知道你很聪明
They know how smart you are.
那可不一定
I'm not sure they do.
他们当然知道
Of course they do.
你没必要一直提醒他们
You don't have to keep reminding them.
应该谦逊点
It's called being humble.
谦逊  你知道这个词吗
Have you heard that word before?
听着  这是我们第一次约会
Look, we're on our first date
是来看这个物理讲座的
And I've come to a physics talk, okay?
你也应该放下架子
You have to bend a little bit too.
谦逊  是吗
Humble, eh?
也许我可以试试
I'll guess I can try anything once.
地球
Earth...
我们的星球  我们的家
Our home, our planet,
生命在此孕育
The very vessel of life.
我们的家园  独一无二不可取代
Our world-- unique, irreplaceable.
可是  有时
And yet, at times,
我们冷酷无情的索求
It seems like we are unrelenting in our quest
使生态系统遭到毁灭性的破坏
To drive our ecosystem into catastrophic failure.
毫无节制
Gone unchecked,
全球变暖将使当如今繁华的世界
Global warming will transform this lush world we know today
寸草不生  毫无生机
Into a lifeless and arid rock.
朋友们  危险在步步紧逼
Friends, the stakes couldn't be higher,
情况已迫在眉睫
The situation no more dire.
是时候采取行动了
It's time... to act.
大家好  我是马尔科姆·托尼
Hello. I'm malcolm tunney.
如果他真的担心全球变暖
If he's so worried about global warming,
为什么要用私人飞机接我们
Why did he fly us here on a private jet
比瑞典排放的二氧化碳都多
That spews out more co2 than sweden?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
非常好
Very kind.
众所周知
As many of you know,
我并不是个环境学家
I am not an environmental scientist,
我也不会假装是
Nor do I pretend to be one.
譬如说  我经常洗澡
For instance, I shower regularly.
别介意  拉里
No offense, larry.
我只是一个心系地球的公民
I'm just a concerned citizen,
长久以来它爱护着我们人类
One who realizes that the earth has carried us for so long,
也许是时候回报她了
Maybe it's time that we carried her.
他还真是
That ratio would be accurate
够自大的
If his body was the size of his ego.
是啊  有点
Yeah, it's a little much.
解决类似全球变暖问题
Solving a problem like global warming
复杂到难以想象
May seem impossibly complex.
如此多的国家  如此多的企业
So many nations, so many corporations,
所以我们每个人
And john q. public
必须要面对许多问题
Will have to agree on a dizzying number of issues.
那么  个人能做些什么
So, then, what can one person really do
改变现状呢
To make a difference?
而我
What can i,
和我那无与伦比的技术
With my particular and unique skill set,
又该怎么办呢
Do to help?
他们认为你自命不凡
They think you're the arrogant one?
在过去的十年里
I've been working on a number of projects
我做了一些研究
Over the last decade,
然后我发现  总结成果
And I realized that, if I were to combine them,
便有意想不到的收获
I just may be able to achieve something unexpected...
所以  女士们先生们
So, ladies and gentlemen,
在科瑞玛创新公司
With major funding
朋友的资金支持下
From my friends at kramer innovations,
我设计了一个方法
I have been able to devise a means
能够安全可控的冷却我们的地球
To cool our planet in a safe and controlled way.
这家伙不知道什么叫冷却
This guy wouldn't know cool--
这背后的科学理论非常复杂
Now, the science behind this is immensely complex,
在你们离开讲厅前
But there will be detailed briefs
会详细的介绍给你们
Handed out to you as you leave the lecture hall,
但现在
But for right now,
让我来简单的解释一下
Let me just give you the  cliffs notes.
首先是这个巨大的吸热设备
It begins with a massive heat-sink,
我的设计之一
One of my own design,
能够从周围环境中
Which steadily draws heat
稳定的吸收热量
From the surrounding environment.
吸收的热量怎么办
But where does the heat go?
也许你会问
Where does that heat go,
吸收的热量怎么办
You may ask.
是的  朋友们  这才是最棘手的部分
Well, my friends, that is the hard part.
用托尼时空物质通道
I give you the tunney space-time matter bridge.
等等  什么
Wait. what?
现在  这不仅仅是理论证明
Now, this isn't just some theoretical math proof.
这已经在技术上投入使用了
This is a functioning piece of technology,
简单的说就是把此空间中的热量
One that literally moves heat from our space time
传到彼空间
And vents it out into another space time.
那是我的通道
That's my bridge...
我和我妹妹想出来的
My sister and I came up with that.
抱歉
Shh. sorry.
这个方法行得通
And it works.
为这个系统  我们做了几个月的实验
We've been testing the system for a few months now,
结果证明系统非常稳定
And it has proved to be remarkably stable.
那是我的想法
That's my idea!
罗德尼  现在不是时候说这个
Rodney, now is not the time.
为了做个示范
For the purposes of the demonstration today,
我在设备周围加了
I've surrounded this facility
电子隔离网
With an electrified plasma grid
其中的吸热器
That will contain the reach of the heat-sink.
只会吸收该建筑内的热量
It will draw heat only from this facility.
等等  他要当场开机器
Wait, he's going to turn it on With us here.
这  这可不行
That's-- this is a bad idea.
罗德尼  拜托
Rodney, please.
为了证明它行之有效
And to prove the effectiveness of this system,
我会把该建筑的温度降低十度
I will lower the temperature within this facility By 10 degrees.
不过别担心
Oh, and don't worry,
我已经关了空调
I've turned off the air conditioning,
保证不会骗你们
So there'll be no cheating, I promise.
抱歉  我不能让他这么做
I'm sorry, I can't let him do this--
不  罗德尼
No, rodney--
打断一下
Excuse me!
马尔科姆
Malcolm...
麦凯博士
Dr. mckay.
谢谢您能来
Thank you for coming.
你不能这么做
This is a bad idea.
我们还没开始互动问答部分
Well, we're not quite ready for the q&a session yet,
可以等一下再发表观点吗
So if you could just wait till then--
还是先让我们看看你的研究数据
Let's just take a look at the data you've come up with
讨论一下
And talk about this,
因为在这么多人的场合下开机器
Because turning the device on with all these people here
太危险了
Could be very dangerous.
尊重的说  我不同意
Respectfully, I disagree.
你不能未经允许就这么做
Wh-- you can't do something like this Without our consent.
坐下
Sit down!
在进场时你签了协议  不是吗
You did sign the document when you entered, didn't you?
是的  我以为那只是
Well, yeah, I thought that was just--
那么你已经同意了
Then I have your consent.
好吧  可是
Yeah, but--
我也在研究一个项目
Look, I've been doing work
和这个非常相似
That is very, very similar to this--
是吗
Really?
我认为这不能
I don't think that's possible.
那个连接其他空间的通道
Look, these bridges to other space times
很难预测
Can be very unpredictable.
你有什么研究成果
Do you have any research
现在就要发布吗
You'd like to put forward right now?
论文之类的
A paper, perhaps?
任何成果足以支持你的观点
Anything to back up your claim?
罗德尼  拜托
Rodney, please.
你不是在嫉妒我吧
Tell me this isn't just petty jealously.
好了
Okay.
不  我只是
Well, no, no, i-- I just--
我不这么认为
No, I didn't think so.
别担心  各位
Don't worry, everyone.
这个示范完全安全
This is completely safe.
那么
And...
我们开始了
We're up and running.
等你们读了简介
Now, I'll be happy to answer all of your questions
我将很乐意回答你们的问题
Once you've had a chance to read the brief,
但现在
But for now,
我们何不回到休息室
Why don't we all go back out to the lobby
来杯热可可呢
Where hot cocoa is waiting,
这儿马上会变得非常冷
'cause it's about to get very cold in here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我
I--
来吧
Come on.
我们去喝杯热巧克力  好吗
Let's go get some hot chocolate, okay?
这
This is...
他是怎么知道我的项目的
How did he even get ahold of my work?
你肯定这是你的项目成果
You're sure this is your work?
绝对肯定
Absolutely.
你相信我  是吗
Look, you believe me, don't you?
我当然相信你
Of course I do.
他不可能是自己想到的
There is no way that he came up with this On his own.
我们要   要
We've got to-- we've got to--
过来
We... come on.
我们不应该进来
We shouldn't be in here.
你站在那望风
Okay, just stand guard there.
等我花几秒钟
It'll take me a couple of seconds
黑入他的电脑
To hack into his computer.
你在做什么
What are you doing?!
谢谢
Thank you.
十分感谢
Thank you, but I don't think
我想如此伟大的成就
An achievement of this magnitude
还是要归功于大家
Can truly be credited to one man.
托尼博士
Dr. tunney, sir.
抱歉
Oh, excuse me.
怎么了
Yes? what is it?
你吩咐我们一旦降到64度
Well, you told us to shut the device down
就关掉设备
Once we reached 64.
是的  对啊  现在可以关设备了
Yes, that's right. we can shut it down now.
问题是  我们试过了
Well, that's the problem, sir. we've tried.
事实上我们尽了最大的努力
We've tried everything, in fact.
可设备关不上
The device won't shut off
马尔科姆
Malcolm...
对不起  给我几分钟
I'm sorry, could you just give me a moment here?
让我来
Let me in here.
好的  都有谁来过这
All right, now, who's been in here?
只有我们  先生
Just us, sir.
什么问题
What is it?
通道无法关上
Well, the bridge won't deactivate.
我也不知道为什么
I don't understand why it shouldn't.
关掉建筑的电源
Shut down the power to the facility.
呃  那没用
Uh, that won't do anything.
一旦运行  这个系统便
The system self-generates its own power
自行供电
Once it's up and running.
那就关掉封闭区部分
Then shut down the containment field.
我们得让客人离开
We need to get these guests out of here.
那也没用
That won't work either.
为什么
Why not?
这十分复杂
Well, it's impossibly complicated,
封闭区跟设备的最基本部分紧密相连
But the containment field is tied into the basic operations of the device.
也就是说  它完全关不了
It literally can't shut down
除非我们把物质通道毁了
Until we collapse the matter bridge.
这是个保险协议
It's a safety protocol,
除非我们能中断设备
One that I can't reprogram
否则我无法重新编程
Until we can power down the device.
那我们被困在这里了
So we're trapped in here
除非你能把这些搞定
Until you can get this thing fixed?
没错
Yes.
到时候怎么办
What happens until then?
这通道会一直通过吸热设备
The bridge will continue to draw heat
吸收热量
From the heat-sink.
十分钟内已经降了十度
We just dropped 10 degrees in 10 minutes.
一个小时内  会低于零度
In an hour, we'll be below zero.
我们会冷死的
We're going to freeze to death.
我已经启动了建筑的供热系统
Well, I've activated the facility's heating system.
会为我们争取点时间
That should buy us a little bit of time.
你说"一切顺利"  你做了很多测试
You said "without a hitch," you'd run hundreds of tests.
有人干扰了系统
Someone has messed with the system.
太出格了
That was out of line, man.
他偷了我的成果
He stole the work.
他当时还在做演讲啊
Hey, come on.It was in the middle of his presentation.
他就要启动了
He was about to start the thing up!
不能再等了
It couldn't wait.
他请你来是出于好意
He brought you here as an olive branch.
想跟你重归于好
He wanted to bury the hatchet.
没错  背着我
Yeah, in my back.
麦凯博士  凯勒医生
Dr. mckay? dr. keller?
什么事
Yes?
托尼先生想跟你们说句话
Mr. tunney would like a word.
我猜  那个字就是"抱歉"
Well, I'm guessing that that word is "i apologize."
已经两字了  天才
That's, uh, two words, genius.
真是个怪胎
That's one odd duck, that guy.
男子汉勇于承认错误
Well, it takes a big man to admit that he's wrong,
我很欣赏
And much as I appreciate it,
但我还是希望道歉过程
I really would prefer that this whole apology thing
能更公开
Took place a little more publicly.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
你才应该
You are the one
向我道歉
Who should be apologizing to me.
道什么鬼歉啊
What the hell for?
我邀请你来是出于礼貌
I invited you here as a courtesy.
出于好意
Out of kindness.
大家都认为
You know, most people think
你疯了
You've lost your mind,
才会去霍华德·休斯医学研究所
That you've gone, uh,howard hughes
我不再联系
Just because I don't call anymore
并不代表我脑子有问题
Doesn't mean I'm keeping my urine in jars.
听着  我不需要你...
Look, I don't need you to--
闭嘴  我没空听这些
Shut up. I don't have time for this.
你们两个干了什么
What have you two done?
我们干了什么
What have we done?
我们关不了设备
We can't shut the device down.
我告诉过你别打开它
I told you not to turn it on.
我几乎是求你的
I practically begged you.
但你们有听吗  没有
But would you listen? no!
告诉我们你们做了什么
Tell us what you did
还有怎么解决
And how to undo it
我就考虑不告你们
And I'll consider not pressing charges.
我们什么都没做
We didn't do anything.
真的吗
Oh, really?
那解释一下这个
Explain this, then.
我们真不该在这
We shouldn't be in here.
-站在那里把风  -为什么
-Stand guard there.  -Why
我需要点时间黑进他的电脑
It'll take me a couple seconds to hack into his computer.
你在干嘛啊?!
What are you doing?!
如果那个混蛋以为在同行面前
If that son of a bitch thinks that he can humiliate me
羞辱了我还能逍遥自得
In front of my peers and get away with it,
那他就等着吧
He's got another thing coming.
我会毁了他
I will destroy him.
不是现在  罗德尼
Now is not the time, rodney.
这里肯定有什么
Got to be something in here I can use
能让他身败名裂
To discredit the pretentious tool.
快点  快点  有人来了
Hurry up, hurry up, somebody's coming.
过来  过来
Come on, come on, come on.
听着  我想你们断章取义
Now, look, I can see how, out of context,
会牵连到...
That could seem incriminating...
断章取义
Out of context?
你在那干什么
What were you doing in there?
我找我在两年前
I was looking for a paper I published
发表的一篇文章
A little over two years ago,
关于物质通道的
One that dealt with a matter bridge.
罗德尼
Rodney,
你已经很久没发表文章了
You have not published a paper in a very long time.
大概你不知道那是我的成果
You probably didn't even know it was my work.
现在你用笔名发表文章吗
Oh, you're publishing under a  nom de plume  now?
好吧  我想该这么说了
Okay, here's how I think it went down--
你在为政府工作
You were working with the government.
有人很相信你
Someone there trusted you a lot
然后让你看了一些不该看的东西
And let you see something you weren't supposed to see.
或者你可能意外地收到了一些东西  谁知道呢
Or maybe you were sent something by accident, who knows.
你看到一篇关于物质通道的文章
You saw a paper about a matter bridge,
一个被叫停的计划
A project that was shut down
因为外来粒子的副作用
Due to the adverse effects of exotic particles.
你看到了
You read it,
你发现如果通道只用来
You realized that if the bridge was used
传送能量
Merely as a transfer of energy, say heat,
就不会产生外来粒子
There would be no exotic particle creation
也不会有副作用
And thus no adverse effects.
所以...
So...
你将其占为己有
You co-opted the science as your own,
稍作改变就飘飘然了
Made a few changes to make yourself feel better,
就那样做了
And got to work,
不顾原作者关于
Dismissing the original authors' warnings
时空通道固有不稳定的警告
About the inherent instability of time-space bridges.
怎么样
How am I doing so far?
那太荒谬了
That's preposterous.
托尼博士研究这个很多年了
Dr. tunney's been working on this for years.
那是我的成果  马尔科姆
That was my work, malcolm.
那文章是我写的
I wrote that paper.
特伦斯
Terrence
他们也许能帮我们
These people may be able to help us.
这太糟了
This is bad.
毁坏吗
The sabotage?
毁坏  求你了
Sabotage. please.
但是你说那...
But you said there was--
我太早下结论了
I may have rushed to judgment.
你能关了它吗
Can you shut it down?
听着  这些物质通道
Look, these matter bridges
难以预测
Are the very definition of unpredictable.
我想得你以前说过的
You know, I think I remember you saying
关于这个
Something about that before.
有还是没有  博士?
Yes or no, doctor?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
你们开始供热了吗
Have you turned up the heat?
是的
Yes.
你有没有注意到这个
Have you noticed this?
有
Yes.
那是什么
What is it?
通道通过吸热器吸收的能量
The bridge isn't drawing a consistent load
并不稳定
From the heat-sink.
相反  是有波动的
Instead, it's wavering.
那有什么糟的
Why is that bad?
不至于说糟吧
I wouldn't necessarily call it bad.
但的确不好
It's definitely not good,
也不知道多不好算糟
But I don't know that I'd call it bad.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding me, right?
正常的通道
A regular bridge
无论何时都会吸收
Should draw the same amount of energy
等量的热能
At all times.
但这个波动得很厉害
This one is fluctuating greatly.
或许能为我所用
Maybe we can use that...
等它到了极限
Wait for it to peak,
就会超负荷  然后崩溃
Then overload it and crash.
好主意
That's a good idea.
对  我就知道你会喜欢
Yeah, I thought you'd like it...
跟我的主意有关的东西
What with it being my idea and all.
这儿真冷
It's freezing in here.
知道了
We get it. it works.
关掉它
Shut it down.
我冷的快粘到椅子上了
I'm starting to freeze to my chair.
搞什么鬼
What the hell was that?
一束突然的急速冷冻光
A sudden and dramatic cooling beam.
从通道射出的不规则能量
The irregular power pull from the bridge...
当通道向吸热器突然吸收能量时
Oh, so when the bridge makes a sudden demand on the heat-sink...
吸热器
The heat-sink reacts
向封闭区内某一固定点
By drawing power from a single, localized place
吸收能量
Inside the containment field.
那光把挡路的所有东西冷冻
And that beam would freeze anything in its path.
天哪  不会吧
Oh, did not see this coming.
简直是冰闪
It's freeze lightning.
冰闪...太赞了
Freeze lightning... ooh, I like that.
甭想了  那是我的
Oh, you can't have it. it's mine.
你是盗版
It's copywritten.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
他整个变形了
He's in very bad shape.
他左半边身子都冻的发亮了
It's like his whole left side has been flash-frozen.
我闻所未闻
I have never seen anything like this before.
天啊
Oh, man.
听着  这不全是你的错
Look, this isn't entirely your fault.
我真希望他签了弃权书
I... I really hope he signed his waiver.
你认为这种情况是
Do you think this is the first time
第一次发生吗
This has happened?
也许这只是第一次
Yeah, or maybe just the first time
有人看到
Anyone's been around to notice it.
这东西会毁掉整栋建筑的
So this thing could be wreaking havoc all over the facility.
会一直发生吗
So this is going to keep happening?
没错  也许会更频繁
Yes, and probably with greater frequency.
好了  这一点副作用
Okay, this little side effect
会妨碍我们关掉它
Is going to really hamper our attempts to shut this thing down.
你用"妨碍"二字
And by "hamper",
是说"我们都会死"吗
You mean "get us all killed."
没错  貌似这样
Yeah,something like that.
我们得通知军队
We need to call in the military.
我想还是先不要
I'd prefer not to do that just yet.
你们真幸运  外面那个人还没死
You're lucky that guy out there isn't dead.
我肯定你们两个
I'm sure these two
能把那设备调回正常的运作模式
Can get the device back into its proper operating mode.
这有点太迟了
It's a little late for that.
特伦斯  事态已经失控
Terrence, things have gotten out of hand.
我们得通知他们了
We need to make that call.
打了电话  政府会监禁我们的
We make that call, the government shuts us down.
对  真不错
Yeah, that's the idea.
我不明白
I don't understand.
设备开始出故障时
When the device started to malfunction,
你想做的第一件事
The first thing you wanted to do
就是把所有人安全送走
Was get everyone out of here safely.
为了避免计划被禁止
To avoid the project being branded
因为继续进行太危险了
As too dangerous to move forward.
现在木已成舟啦
Well, the cat's out of the bag now.
你是不是担心
Are you worried about all the money
你投进去的钱  打水漂啦
You sunk into this? 'cause that's gone.
不是  我不是担心钱
No, I'm not worried about the money.
我们就快解决
We're close to coming up with a solution
全球变暖了
For global warming.
我们能拯救这个星球
We could save the planet.
这比我重要  也比你重要
It's bigger than me, and it's bigger than you.
要是我们能控制那设备
If we can get the device under control
而不必惊动军队
Without calling the military,
他们就会让我们继续研究
They're going to let us continue our research.
那我告诉你
I've got news for you.
你搞不定了
You can't control it,
而且你不应该再继续研究了
And you shouldn't continue with your research.
我们会解决的
We'll figure it out.
我给了你们极大的信任
I have the utmost faith in both of you.
真荒谬
This is ridiculous.
把你的电话给我
Give me your cell.
没用的
It won't work,
在封闭区不起作用
Not with the containment field up.
干扰太强
There's too much interference.
你办公室里有电话
You have a land line in your office.
没声音
It's dead.
给我试试
Give me that.
没声音
It's dead.
肯定是克雷默掐断了电话线
Kramer must have killed the phones.
估计你也进不了
I don't suppose you have access
通信室
To the communications room?
是克雷默的地盘
It's a kramer facility.
我只是在那工作
I just work here.
棒极了
Great.
貌似就指望咱俩了
Looks like it's up to you and me.
我们最好快回控制室
We'd better get back to the control room,
自己把它修好
Figure this out ourselves.
等等  等等
Wait. wait, wait.
那儿不是有
Isn't there, like,
一屋子天才吗
A room full of geniuses out there?
就他们?
That's debatable.
再来个那种冰闪
If that freeze lightning thing happens again,
人就死光了
People could die.
他们会拖我后腿的
They'll slow me down.
我们今天说好的
Hey! what happened to that "humble" thing
"谦逊"哪儿去了
We were going to try today?
结果是
...the result
我们所称的  冰闪
Is what I am calling "freeze lightning."
难以置信
Unbelievable.
是在固定点发生的
It is the sudden and immediate transfer of heat
瞬间能量转换
From a localized area,
其潜在能量足以致命
And it is potentially very lethal.
我们得想办法毁掉物质通道
We need to figure out how to collapse the matter bridge,
阻止其从吸热器吸收能量
Stop it from drawing energy from the heat-sink,
否则这儿迟早会冻死人
Otherwise it's going to get "unlivably" cold in here.
为什么我们不把这封闭区关上
Why don't we just turn this containment field off
然后离开呢
And get out of here?
好吧  首先
Well, for one thing,
这与物质通道的基本操作
It's tied into the basic function
紧密相关
Of the matter bridge,
所以不能只是关上
So we can't just shut it off.
就算关得上
Even if we could,
它储存了这么多冷空气
It houses so much cool air now
一旦被毁就会导致
That it would create a sudden, massive cold front
突如其来的寒流
As soon as it drops.
于是暴风  龙卷风
We're talking high-speed winds, tornadoes...
席卷而来
An instant mega-storm.
更不用提
Not to mention the fact
吸热器就会吸收
That the heat-sink would start to draw heat
不仅仅是该建筑的
Not just from this facility,
乃至整个星球的热量
But from the entire planet.
我们必须阻止它发生
We cannot allow that to happen.
为什么不能毁了它  把它砸了
Why don't we just destroy it, just bash it apart?
可能会引起时空裂缝
Because that could create a tear in our space time.
还是算了吧
Never mind, then.
对
Yeah.
听着  你们是精英中的精英
Look, you guys are the best of the best.
我想你们研究研究一定会有办法
I'm sure if you work together, you'll come up with something.
这样肯定不行  听着
That will never work. look.
给我两秒钟足够了
Just give me two seconds...
不
No!
你错的一塌糊涂
You're going about this all wrong.
注意点你在挑谁的错
Watch who you're correcting,
"赛先生"
"science guy."
我的博士学位可不是混来的
My ph.d. is not honorary.
听着  我是工程师  我会做数学
Hey, look, I'm an engineer. I can do math!
听我说就行了
Just listen to my idea--
我听着呢  听到让我觉得
I have been listening, and that is what led me to believe
你是个智障
That you are a moron!
令人欣慰的是  你们俩都错了
If it's any consolation, you're both wrong.
什么  难道你对吗
What, and you're right?
我们还要听你的
We're supposed to listen to you?
就是你这个混蛋把我们搅得一团糟
You're the jerk that got us into this mess.
我的理论能行
I have a workable theory.
是啊  "理论"
Yeah, a "theory".
考虑到我有这方面充足经验
Take into account that I have experience with this,
我几年前做这个时
That I've been doing work that is years ahead
你们还在痴人说梦话呢
Of anything you guys have even been dreaming about?
我正有此意
I think that's kind of what I'm getting at!
真丢人
This is embarrassing.
瞧瞧你们
Look at you--
这个世界上最伟大的思想者
The greatest minds this world has to offer,
要是我不知道你们的身份
And if I didn't know any better,
还以为这是一群六年级的小学生
I'd think there was a bunch of sixth graders in here.
你们还不赶快闭嘴合作
You guys need to suck it up and get along.
就像我常说的
It's like I've always said,
人与人之间更为相似...
People are more alike than they are different--
拜托  耐
Not now, nye.
好吧
Okay.
我们的生命危在旦夕
Our lives are at stake here.
我们需要一个解决方案
We need a solution,
而且越快越好
And we need this fast.
努点力
Please...
加油啊  所以人都在指望你们
Come on, the rest of us are counting on you.
好  罗德尼
Yes, rodney.
我貌似有想法了
I think I'm onto something.
我得平静一下
It just needs some ironing out.
很好  看到没
Okay. Great.
伙计们
Guys...
是啊  好吧
Yeah, well,
我们现在好好看看
Let's have a look at it and just...
理清思路
Fresh eyes.
先从比尔的理论开始
We'll start with bill's theory...
他们能想出办法的
They'll figure something out.
我也相信他们能
I'm sure they will.
但愿赶在有人死掉之前吧
Let's just hope it's before someone dies.
我叔叔乔治
You know, my uncle george,
非常厌恶人说
He always hated the phrase
拯救地球
"save the planet".
为什么
What?
他只是认为这种想法太过时了
Well, he just thought it was a little backwards,
地球就在这
You know, 'cause the planet's going to be here
不论发生什么
No matter what happens.
也许会变得难以生存
It might be a giant unlivable rock,
但我们会挺过来的
But it's going to survive.
你是想把话题转为
So you're turning this
语言学的讨论吗
Into a discussion on semantics?
我的意思是  克拉默先生
What I mean is, mr. kramer,
你所做的不是拯救地球
The work you're doing isn't about saving the planet.
而是拯救生命
It's about saving lives.
这是一项神圣的职责
And that's a noble pursuit,
去救亿万民众
Trying to save billions of people...
即使是救几百人也是神圣的
But it's no less noble to save a hundred.
这些人  不论多聪明
These guys, no matter how smart they are,
他们一样需要帮助
They could use some help.
只要一个电话就能让他们活着出去
One phone call could get that help here.
现在  求你了
Now, please...
让我打个电话吧
Please let me make that call.
天啊  别吓我
Oh, don't tell me.
我的老天
Oh, god.
十分抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
你能修吗
Can you fix it?
不  我们现在完全与世隔绝了
No. we're completely cut off.
真是坏消息
Well, that's terrible news.
都是我的错  我应该
It's my fault. I should have--
是啊  你应该
Yeah, you should have.
你该看看这个
You need to see this.
冷空气
Oh, the cold temperatures
正在影响封闭区发射器
Are affecting the containment field emitters.
如果系统变弱了  就濒临损毁了
When they're weak, they're on the verge of failing.
那很好啊
That's great.
我们能把大多数人
We can get most of the people
转移出去  对吧
Out of here, no?
给军方打个电话
Make a call to the military?
我们周围空气温度很高
We're surrounded by desert air.
而封闭区内的气温
The temperatures inside the containment field
越来越冷了
Has gotten very, very cold.
冰冷空气的突然喷发
Introducing a sudden and immediate blast of icy air
会引起可怕的漩涡风暴
Will create one hell of a vortex storm.
传输器不可能通过
No way a cell transmission could make it through,
更别说让人安全出去
Let alone actually get people out of here safely.
我们经受得住风暴
We can ride out the storm.
不行  除非我们关闭设备
No, if we can't shut down the device,
否则气温系统会源源不断的
The heat-sink's going to keep feeding cold air
放出冷空气
Into that weather system.
永无止境
It'll never stop.
这可不好
That's not good.
我还是希望它别发生
No, I'd rather that didn't happen.
不不不
No, no, no, no.
这说不定是好事
This might be a good thing.
什么意思
What is it?
这个封闭区
Well, the containment field
在持续缓慢的消亡
Is dying a slow but consistent death.
现在它已经很弱了
It might be weak enough
足够我们往外拨一个手机信号
To actually punch a cell phone signal through now.
好吧
Oh, you know,
也许你说得对
You might be right.
好  这可能是我们的一线生机
Okay, this is probably our best bet.
这两个辐射源是最弱的
These two emitters are the weakest.
这得争分夺秒
It's a bit of a run from here,
我最好现在就去
So I'd better get going right now.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
给我你电话
Give me your cell.
我们需要您在这里帮助解除通道
We need you here to help dismantle the bridge.
我来打电话
I'll make the call.
我
I--
来吧
Come on.
好  好
All right, all right.
好
Fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
我一旦接通就通知你们
I'm going to radio once I get through.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你也是
You too.
她看起来是个女强人
She seems like a very capable woman.
当然
She sure is.
他是你妹妹吧
She's your sister, right?
单身?
Is she single?
好了  刚说到哪儿了
All right, where were we?
你的想法
Your idea
在通道毁掉的一瞬击垮它
Of overwhelming the bridge to the point of collapse,
是个好主意
It's a good one.
非常正确
It's right on track.
不过
But...
我们都认为这意味着
Everybody here thinks it means
要接通吸热器
We've got to dial up the heat-sink.
气温就会更低
It's going to get even colder.
可能会引起
And that could result
大量难以预料冰闪
In an unpredictable amount of freeze lightning...
把我们全冻死
Which could kill us all.
正确
Right.
该建筑的锅炉垮了
The facility's furnace just went down.
为什么会这样
Well, how did that happen?
我们上个小时开了120%的马力
We've been running at 120% for the last hour
补偿失去的热能
To compensate for falling temperatures.
我们在沙漠中心
We're in the middle of the desert.
建筑不用如此供热
The facility's not meant to be heated like this.
我们马上就会冻成冰棍
We'll get below freezing pretty darn quick now.
好吧  我们不能关了电源
All right, well, we can't power it down
因为它自己供电
'cause it generates its own power.
我们也不能等
And we can't wait
因为封闭区就要崩溃了
For the containment field to collapse
暴风会杀死我们
Because the storm will probably kill us.
伙计们  我们别无选择
Guys, we don't have a choice, okay.
一旦通道达到顶峰
We've got to wait for the bridge to peak,
就接通吸热器  看能不能克服它
Dial up the heat-sink, see if we can overwhelm it.
我知道很危险  但我们得破釜沉舟了
I know it's dangerous, but that's all we've got.
好吧  听着
Okay, look.
这儿人太多了
There's too many people in here.
我还有重要工作
I have important work to do.
你们不要妨碍我
I do not need you in the way,
所有人  出去
So, everybody, out!
快点
Oh, come on.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
兰德指挥办公室
General landry's office.
你好  我是珍妮弗·凯勒医生
Yes, this is dr. jennifer keller.
我必须立即跟总指挥说话
I need to speak to the general immediately.
情况紧急
It's an emergency.
喂
Hello?
喂  这里是
Hello? this is dr.--
喂
Hello?
娘的
Son of a bitch!
要警告大家我们要开始了吗
Should we warn everyone we're about to do this?
不用  会引起恐慌的
No, no, that would just cause a panic.
他们最好不知道
It's probably better they don't know.
我们无法将人群转移到安全地带
We have no way of moving people to a safe area,
而且我们也不知道
Plus we have no idea
下一个冰闪
Where the next freeze lightning strike
会击中谁
Could hit.
冰闪
"freeze lightning--"
名字够烂的
You know, that's a bad name.
别看我  是他想出来的
Don't look at me. it's his idea.
好了  开始吧
Okay, here we go.
好了  快关了
All right, shut it off.
不行  通道还没垮掉呢
I can't. it hasn't collapsed the bridge yet.
刚刚有信号的
I had a signal before.
快点
Come on!
没用
It's not working!
还需要一点时间  一点点
We just need a little more time, a little more time.
冰闪
The lightning strikes
把整个建筑都冻起来了
Are freezing off whole sections of the facility.
大家都被隔离了
Everyone is getting isolated.
没关系了
It doesn't matter.
只要我们能关了它  迟早会化的
They'll melt eventually if we can shut this thing down.
你会把我们都害死的
You are going to kill us all!
听着  我得一直
Look, I just need to keep doing--
你做了什么
What did you do?
关了它
I turned it down.
什么  为什么
What? why?
太危险了
It was too dangerous.
但就快成功了啊
But we were almost there.
就要达到峰值了  就要成功了
It was peaking out! it was going to work.
是啊  那我们就都挂了
Yeah, and we'd all be dead.
得想点别的法子
We have to come up with something else.
是啊  还有更快的么
Yeah, something fast!
封闭区就快垮了
'cause the containment field is about to fail.
好极了
Great.
不太好
Oh, not good.
罗德尼  听到吗
Rodney, can you hear me?
拜托告诉我你接通了星门控制中心
Please tell me you got through to the sgc?
没有
No.
那你得再试试
You've got to keep trying.
我想啊  但手机有点进水了
I'd love to, but my phone got a little soaked.
它都不开机了
It's not even... turning on.
什么
What?
走廊被冰闪击中了
My hallway got hit by that freeze lightning thing.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
目前没事  过一会儿就不好说了
I am now, but I won't be for long.
发生了什么
What happened?
我被封在里面了
I'm frozen in.
水管也被炸开
And the pipes busted open.
我的体温在急剧下降
My body temperature is dropping really fast.
好吧  我去通知安全人员
Okay, I'll radio security.
马上派人找她
I'll get someone out to her right away.
听着  保安就来了
Look, security's on the way.
你好好等着
I need you just to sit tight
尽量保持温暖  懂么
And try to stay warm, okay?
好的
Okay.
很抱歉没能接通电话
Sorry I didn't get the call through.
你尽力了
You did your best.
你把那玩意儿关了吗
Did you shut down that thing down?
还没  我们还在努力
Not yet. we're working on it.
加油
Hurry.
是啊
Yeah.
麦凯
Mckay!
听着  我得走了
Okay, look, I've got to go.
人马上就到  好吧
Someone's on the way, all right.
怎么啦
What is it?
封闭区崩溃  倒数计时
Containment field failure
3  2  1
In 3... 2... 1...
高空风
Winds aloft.
逐渐达到危险程度
Reaching dangerous levels.
如果持续下去
If it continues like this,
我们就等着看龙卷风吧
We'll have a mess of tornadoes on our hands.
好极了  或许之前我们就挂了
Great. Even less time before we died.
听着  这个设备不是能自己供电吗
Look, this device is capable of generating its own power, right?
是的  我们转换其中一小部分能量
Yeah, a small percentage of the energy we're transferring
用来支撑设备
Is siphoned off to power the device.
只要它在运作  就是自给自足的
So once it's running, it's self-sustaining.
所以我们不能拔了插头了事
Which is why we can't just pull the plug.
的确
Exactly.
但它只是在一定程度上自我供电
But it's only capable of powering itself to a certain extent?
它总有个发电能量的极限吧
It has a finite amount of power generation capability?
是啊  当然
Well, yes, of course.
也许我们一直在南辕北辙
Maybe we've been approaching this the wrong way.
我们一直在给通道
We've been trying to force so much power
提供能量
Through the bridge
才造成了超负荷
That it overloads it.
或许应该将其消耗殆尽
Maybe we should starve it--
从发电机吸收能量
Suck so much power from its generator
直至其瘫痪
That it stalls it out.
从技术上说是可行的
Technically, we could do that,
但得从电源中吸收大量能量
But you'd have to draw an insane amount of power.
吸热器都做不到
The heat-sink could never do it.
是不行
No...
但再来一个时空通道或许可以
But another space-time bridge could.
你想再打开一个时空通道
You want to open another space-time bridge?
既然设备不能开一个时空通道
The device was rigged to power a single bridge.
那我们就再开一个
We open another one...
只要它压制住系统  它就会停了
And it overwhelms the system and it fails.
肯定行的
It'll work.
是啊  但你想过没
Y-yeah, but do you have any idea
配置系统使其
How difficult it will be
能同时开两个时空通道
To configure the system
有多难吗
To open two concurrent space-time bridges?
我没说过这很简单啊
I never said it was going to be easy.
简直不可能
Well, it'll be impossible.
拜托  我可是罗德尼·麦凯博士  好吧
Hey, I'm dr. rodney mckay, all right?
"困难"用秒解决  "不可能"用分钟搞定
"difficult" takes a few seconds, "impossible," a few minutes.
罗德尼  能听到吗
Rodney, can you hear me?
他们把你救出来了吗
Have they got you out of there yet?
没有
No.
托尼  刚刚怎么说来着
Tunney, what's the deal?
你不是派了保安了吗
I thought you sent security.
他们无法到她那儿
They can't get to her.
什么  怎么会
What? why not?
刚刚一轮冰闪
Oh, that last round of freeze lightning,
封了许多走廊
It sealed off a lot of the corridors.
看  他们正朝她那儿去呢
See, they're making their way to her,
但得花点时间
But it'll take some time.
越来越难
It's getting harder...
很难保持清醒了
Harder to stay awake.
我快要体温过低了
I'm going into... hypothermic shock.
珍妮弗  坚持住  好吗
Jennifer, just hang in there, all right?
行  我们在这儿
All right, we're here, right?
我们可以去找她  那么近
So we can get to her. it's a straight shot.
他们应该走这条路  穿过实验室
They should have come this way, through the lab.
他们与我们也隔离了
They're cut off from us too.
我要去找她
I've got to go get her.
别  等等  我们现在很忙啊
No, wait. we're a bit busy right now.
她会死的!
She'll die.
如果风暴持续下去
If the storm keeps up like this,
最终会毁掉建筑  我们都会死的
It'll rip the building apart, we'll all die!
上次你声称自己是天才
Last time I checked,
我审核过了
You were claiming to be a genius.
计划我都给你了
I already gave you the plan.
可是漏洞百出
A plan full of holes.
那就填上!
So fill them!
要是出错怎么办
W-what if I run into a problem?
搞定它!
Work around it!
你比我聪明
You're smarter than me.
我知道
I know.
麦凯
Mckay!
真受不了
Oh, this is outrageous!
最需要他的时候  他反倒推给我了
When we need him the most, he puts it on me,
而我应该
And I'm supposed to be the one to--
别像个娘儿们
Man up.
珍妮弗
Jennifer!
好了  就是它了
Okay, I think that's it.
启动之前  检查一下
Before I run it, just check my math.
检查过了
I have been!
不然你以为我在这儿干什么
Why do you think I'm standing here?
珍妮弗
Jennifer!
好了  快点快点
Okay, come on, come on, come on.
开始
Do it!
没呼吸了
You're not breathing.
天哪  没呼吸了
Oh, my god, you're not breathing.
拜托别死啊
Oh, please don't be dead.
千万别死啊
Please don't be dead.
回到我身边  拜托
Come back to me, please.
快醒醒啊
Please come back to me.
成功了
It worked!
第二个时空通道超过了能量供应
The second space-time bridge blew the power supply.
两个通道都垮了
Both bridges collapsed.
成功了
I did it!
拜托
Please...
谢谢老天
Oh, thank god.
你没事吧
You're okay.
You're okay...
我很冷
I'm really cold.
我也是
Me too...
你救了我
You saved me.
那我们扯平了
I guess that makes us even.
我用了把斧子
I used an ax.
大斧子
A big ax.
真希望你当时能看到
I really wish you were conscious,
这是我迄今为止做过的最酷的事
'cause I think it's the coolest thing I've ever done--
真不知道失去了你
I don't know what I would have done
我怎么办
If I lost you...
我爱你
I love you.
已经有段日子了
I have for some time now.
希望你知道
I just wanted you to know.
我
I--
至少你朋友
Well, at least your friends
不再认为你可有可无了
Don't think you're a washout anymore.
白痴比尔·耐
Stupid bill nye
还在到处跟人说
Is telling everyone who will listen
是托尼那家伙关了设备的
That tunney's the guy who turned the device off.
的确是他关上的啊
Because he was the one that shut off the device.
是我的想法  我的点子
With my coding. it was my idea.
罗德尼  真这么要紧吗
Rodney, does it really matter?
是的  当然
Yes. yes, it does.
对不起
I'm sorry,
我知道应该谦逊
I know I'm supposed to be humble,
不应该那么要强
Not supposed to care,
但我就是在意  很在意
But I do, I really do.
但这  这就是你要了解的我
And that's... that's something you should know about me.
那就辞职
Well, quit, then.
去私营部门
Join the private sector.
做些让全世界见证的伟业
Start doing work the whole world can see.
我有想过
I've been thinking about it.
什么  肯定没有
What? no, you haven't.
我和星门控制中心的合约年底到期
My contract with sgc is up this year.
也许是時候继续了  做点别的
Maybe it's time to move on, time to do other things.
拜托
Please...
没什么人比你更爱工作了
I don't know anyone who loves their job more than you.
你说军方会让他们
So you think the military
继续实验吗
Is going to let them keep experimenting?
不太可能了
I think it's highly unlikely.
何况  地球工程前景不好
Besides, geo-engineering is a dumb pursuit anyway.
靠个人不能解决全球变暖问题
No one person's going to solve global warming.
人人有责
We all have to do our part.
例如不搭私人飞机
Like not take private jets.
总有一天他们会理解的
Well, they were going our way anyway.
知道么  只有你和我真好
You know, it's kind of nice, just me and you back here.
是啊
Right.
是啊!
Right!
几小时前你差点挂了
You were legally dead a few hours ago.
你简直冻僵了
You were practically frozen.
你真的想
You really want to...
要么那样
Well, it's either that
要么听你喋喋不休
Or you keep telling me
如何如何拯救了大家
How you, and only you, saved the day.
我努力尝试"谦逊"
I'm trying out this whole "humble" thing out.
看来女士还真吃这一套
Seems to be quite a hit with the ladies...